Shiv Noliyan

ETL Developer

With nearly 3 years of expertise, engaged in Analysis, Design, Development, Implementation, Testing, and Support of ETL processes, Data Warehousing, and Data Integration Solutions using Informatica with a team of 5 for Client (i.e. Levi Strauss & Co.)

shiv.saini.54966@gmail.com

+91 9084684215

Pune, India

linkedin.com/in/shiv-noliyan-a2631a161

•

WORK EXPERIENCE

ETL Informatica Developer (Associate) Cognizant Technology Solutions

06/2021 - 12/2023

Pune, India

Roles & Responsibilities

- Designed and developed ETL pipelines using Informatica, improving data processing speed by 25%.
- Strong experience in Informatica PowerCenter and IICS to create complex mappings, sessions, and workflows, using transformations like Lookup, Joiner, Router, Aggregator, Rank, Union, Sorter, Union, Sequence, etc.
- Knowledge of cloud-based solutions such as <u>ADF</u>, <u>Data</u>
 <u>Lake Store</u>, <u>Blob Storage</u>, <u>Azure Synapse</u>, and <u>Snowflake</u>.
- Proficient in developing SQL with various relational databases such as Oracle and Microsoft SQL Server.
- Involved in <u>performance tuning</u> using <u>Partitioning</u> and <u>Pushdown Opt.</u> to remove source and target bottlenecks.
- Worked on optimizing the mappings by creating <u>reusable</u> transformations, <u>Mapplets</u>, and <u>Worklets</u>. Also, used <u>Informatica scheduler</u>, and <u>BMC Control-M</u> for ETL jobs.
- Provide support for <u>Data migration</u> across Dev, QA, PROD environments and other <u>production support</u> activities.
- Involved in <u>Unit Testing</u>, <u>SIT</u>, and <u>UAT</u> phases of the project with tools like <u>Jira</u>, <u>ServiceNow</u>, and <u>HP ALM</u>.
- Created and maintained system documentation on Confluence, improving team productivity by 15%.

GenC (Generation Cognizant)Cognizant Technology Solutions

01/2021 - 06/2021

Pune, India

Roles & Responsibilities

- Get Hands-on Experience on technology like ETL, SQL, Python, Unix, Data warehouse, Java and Front-end Technologies like HTML, CSS, PHP and JavaScript.
- Under the guidance of Trainer, made a Timesheet Web app for associates which can be managed by Admin.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Personal Website & Portfolio (11/2023)

 Crafted a dynamic portfolio website utilizing HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, spotlighting personal projects and proficiencies.

Power BI Visualization/Reporting (05/2024) &

 Drafted a report utilizing a Customer Transaction Dataset with templates such as Card, Pie/Column chart, Slicer, Map, Q&A etc.

EDUCATION

B.Tech

S.R.M. Institute Of Science and Technology

07/2017 - 06/2021

Kattankulathur, Chennai, India

Courses

Computer Science And Engineering

SKILLS



CERTIFICATES & ACHIEVEMENTS

Informatica PowerCenter (2022) 🗷

Udemy Platform

Informatica Implementation Practitioner (05/2023)
Informatica Platform

The Complete SQL Bootcamp (2022)
Udemy Platform

Linux Command Line Basics (11/2022)

Udemy Platform

Project Pivot Program (10/2023) C

CII Fundamentals Foundational from Cognizant Learn

WORKSHOPS

Business Intelligence using Power BI (05/2024)
Organized by: Jatan Shah (Microsoft Certified Trainer & CEO of Skill Nation)

Google Cloud Study Jam (04/2019)
Organized by: DSC SRM Team

LANGUAGES

English

French

Full Professional Proficiency

Elementary Proficiency

INTERESTS & HOBBIES

Chess Web Development Android Development

Gym/Workout Cricket Music Sci-Fi Movies